<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<modDesc descVersion="79">
    <author>SbSh</author>
	<contributor>Glowin, frvetz, AgrarPlay - LUWZ</contributor>
	<version>1.0.0.01</version>
	<title>
        <en>CVT Addon</en>
    </title>

    <description>
        <en>
<![CDATA[This script adds all vehicles with continuously variable transmissions
a genuine CVT transmission or hydrostatic transmission.
This can be configured in the shop. You can also choose between a classic
or modern variant.
- Realistically, it is always selected to match the vehicle.

Important:
 The key bindings for the CVT add-on must first be assigned.
 All settings in the LS should be set to manual.
 Manual shifting and clutch.
 No automatic control systems may be active.
 If you want to drive realistically, you will do this anyway.
 The CVT addon should be actively used and not just a "it runs in the background" mod
 (customise for the respective application)

Setting options:
 General CVT:
 -4 acceleration ramps can be set.
 -Braking ramps can also be set.
 -TMS pedal mode can be activated.
 -Automatic differential lock can be activated or preselected. This requires the mod
  FS22_VehicleControlAddon or FS22_EnhancedVehicle is required.
 -Efficient working with the machine at maximum power.
 -To be able to start the engine, the clutch must be actuated
  a button or a clutch pedal must be assigned for this purpose.
  This may also be the same clutch that is used for manual transmissions.
 Classic CVT:
 -2 driving ranges can be shifted here.
 Modern CVT:
 -The driving ranges shift automatically.
 -The parking brake is activated as soon as you move away from the driver's seat.
  FS22_VehicleControlAddon or FS22_EnhancedVehicle required.
 -Low-speed concept, enables even more eficient working.
 -Convenient operation thanks to fewer required setting parameters.
 Hydrostat and HST drive:
 -The 2 basic variants are selected by switching the drive ranges.
 -In this configuration, the single acceleration ramps are declared as speed levels.
 -Both hydraulic drive types can be set in motion by a percentage accelerator pedal.
  With the hydrostat (the older or simple variant), the hand throttle must be used to
  A. reach the final speed,
  B. increase the hydraulic pump capacity, e.g. to increase the speed and lifting power
  of the frontloader on the yard or wheelloader
  to achieve more speed and lifting power.
 -In the newer version, this is largely regulated automatically,
  but the hand throttle can still be used to
  to carry out front loader work more agilely.
 -If FS22_VehicleControlAddon is active,
  the parking brake must be applied to start the engine.
 Heat, overheating and wear:
 -Engines must first run warm enough to avoid generating increased wear under load.
 -Improper use and incorrect adjustment when driving, especially under load,
  can cause the gearbox to wear out more quickly.
 -If the pressure is too high, the gearbox can overheat and thus cause wear.
 -The engine temperatures are only synchronised with FS22_DashboardLive in Multiplayer!
  DBL must be active at least with .

Influence on the functions and functions that create influence:
 The engine braking effect:
 -Is calculated dynamically by various factors. Among other things, weight, speed, wind,
  incline or decline play a role, engine power (unfortunately not cubic capacity),
  engine speed range and speed, etc. play a role.
  Also depending on which acceleration ramp is selected.

 Starting the engine:
  For continuously variable vehicles, the clutch must be depressed,
  which must be assigned separately - i.e. the same input,
  which is also the normal clutch. In hydrostatic configuration, if VCA is active
  the handbrake must be applied in order to start the engine.
  In addition, the hand throttle must not be pulled up, it must be set to 0.

 Driving ranges:
  There are 2 driving ranges, II. is intended for road travel, transport and light work.
  Stage I. is more for heavy field work and heavy transport.
  Here the maximum speed is also reduced and the torque provides more thrust,
  especially when starting off.
  A button assignment must be assigned for each level.
  The driving ranges should be changed when the machine is stationary,
  as this can also cause damage. *A little tip, if you use the group shift buttons for up/down,
  you can use the same buttons for the speed steps.
  A special feature of the "modern" configuration is that the driving ranges are regulated.

 Acceleration ramps:
  Furthermore, there is now an acceleration ramp in 4 stages, which can be switched through with one button.
  This influences the acceleration behaviour when accelerating and reducing the driving speed.
  Smooth and with feeling or full power and rough. With heavy implements or trailers,
  can cause high pressure in the planetary gearbox and damage it!
  In this case, the acceleration ramp should be set to 3 or less.
  Level 4 is more suitable for empty runs.
  For light field work, you can easily pull at speed level 1 in acceleration ramp 4 - for example, disc harrow, flat cultivator.

Further detailed explanations of the details
can be found in the Escape help menu and
in the Wiki on Github, as well as tutorial videos.

Almost all values and settings can be used with FS22_DashboardLive.
More detailed informations about it at the wiki on Github.

Feel free to provide ideas, feedback and reports at <a href"https://github.com/s4t4n/FS22_CVT_Addon">Github: FS22_CVT_Addon</a> please.


]]></en>
        <de>
<![CDATA[Dieses Skript fügt allen Fahrzeugen mit stufenlosen Getrieben
ein echtes CVT Getriebe oder auch Hydrostat Getriebe hinzu.
Dies ist im Shop konfigurierbar. Es kann zudem zwischen klassischer
oder moderner Variante gewählt werden.
- Realistisch betrachtet wählt man es immer passend zum Fahrzeug aus.

Wichtiges:
 Die Tasten für das CVT-Addon müssen erst Belegt werden.
 Alle Einstellungen im LS sollten auf manuell gesetzt sein.
 Manuelle Schaltung und Kupplung.
 Es dürfen keine Automatiken für die Steuerung aktiv sein.
 Wenn man realistisch fahren möchte, macht man das sowieso.
 Das CVT-Addon sollte aktiv benutzt werden und nicht nur ein "es läuft im Hintergund" Mod
 ( für die jeweilige Anwendung anpassen )

Einstellungsmöglichkeiten:
 Allgemein CVT:
 -Es können 4 Beschleunigungsrampen eingestellt werden.
 -Ebenso sind Bremsrampen einstellbar.
 -TMS Pedalmodus ist aktivierbar.
 -Automatische Differentialsperre kann aktiviert oder oder vorgewählt werden.
  Hierzu ist der Mod FS22_VehicleControlAddon oder FS22_EnhancedVehicle nötig.
 -Effizientes Arbeiten mit der Maschine, bei maximaler Leistung.
 -Um den Motor starten zu können, muß die Kupplung betätigt werden,
  hierzu muß eine Taste oder ein Kupplungpedal belegt werden.
  Diese darf auch die gleiche Kupplung sein,
  die für manuelle Getriebe verwendet wird.
 
 Klassisches CVT:
 -Hier können 2 Fahrbereiche umgeschalten werden.
 
 Modernes CVT:
 -Die Fahrbereiche schalten automatisch.
 -Die Parkbremse wird aktiviert, sobald man sich vom Fahrersitz entfernt.
  FS22_VehicleControlAddon oder FS22_EnhancedVehicle benötigt.
 -Niedrigdrehzahl-Konzept, ermöglicht ein noch efizienteres Arbeiten.
 -Komfortable Arbeitsweise durch weniger notwendige Einstellungsparameter.
 
 Hydrostat und HST Antrieb:
 -Die 2 Grundvarianten werden durch umschalten der Fahrbereiche gewählt.
 -In dieser Konfiguration werden die einst Beschleunigungsrampen als Geschwinigkeits-Stufen deklariert.
 -Beide hydraulischen Fahrantriebsarten lassen sich durch ein Prozentuales Fahrpedal in Bewegung setzen.
  Beim Hydrostat (die ältere oder einfache Variante),
  muß man das Handgas benutzen um
  A. die Endgeschwindigkeit zu erreichen,
  B. die Hydraulikpumpleistung zu erhöhen, um z.B. den Frontlader am Hof- oder Radlader
  auf mehr Tempo und Hubkraft zu bringen.
 -Bei der neueren Variante wird diese weitgehen automatisch geregelt, dennoch kann man mit dem Handgas
  die Frontladerarbeiten agiler durchführen.
 -Wenn FS22_VehicleControlAddon aktiv ist, muß hier zum Motorstarten die Parkbremse gezogen sein.
 
 Hitze, Überhitzung und Verschleiß:
 -Motoren müssen erst einmal warm genug laufen,
  um nicht unter Last erhöhten Verschleiß zu generieren.
 -Bei unsachgemäßer Benutzung und Falscheinstellung beim fahren,
  vor allem unter Last, kann das Getriebe schneller Verschleißen.
 -Das Getriebe kann bei zu hohem Druck eine Überhitzung erleiden
  und damit den Verschleiß antreiben.
 -Die Motortemperaturen werden nur mit FS22_DashboardLive im Multiplayer syncronisiert!
  Dazu muß DBL mindestens nur mit aktiv sein.

Einfluß auf die Funktionen und Funktionen die Einfluß schaffen:
 Die Motorbremswirkung:
 -Wird durch verschiedene Faktoren dynamisch berechnet.
  U.a. spielen Gewicht, Geschwindigkeit, Wind,
  Steigung oder Gefälle, Motorleistung(Leider kein Hubraum),
  Motordrehzahlband und Drehzahl, uvm. eine Rolle.
  Auch je nachdem welche Beschleunigunsrampe gewählt ist.

 Motor Starten:
  Bei Stufenlosen Fahrzeugen muß die Kupplung getreten werden,
  die separat belegt werden muß - also die selbe Eingabe,
  welche auch die normale Kupplung ist.
  Bei Hydrostatischer Konfiguration muß, wenn VCA aktiv ist,
  die Handbremse gezogen sein um den Motor starten zu können.
  Außerdem darf das Handgas nicht hochgezogen sein, diese muß auf 0 sein.

 Fahrbereiche:
  Es gibt 2 Fahrstufen, II. ist für Straßenfahrten, Transport und leichte Arbeiten gedacht.
  Stufe I. eher für schwere Feldarbeiten und schwere Transporte.
  Hierbei wird auch die Maximalgeschwindigkeit reduziert und
  das Drehmoment sorgt vorallem beim anfahren für mehr Schub.
  Für jede Stufe ist eine Tastenbelegung zu vergeben.
  Das wechseln der Fahrbereiche sollte im Stillstand geschehen,
  da auch hier Schäden entstehen können. *Kleiner Tipp,
  wenn ihr die Gruppenschaltungs-Tasten für hoch/runter nutzt,
  könnt ihr die selben Tasten für die Fahrstufen verwenden.
  Besonderheit bei der "modernen" Konfiguration ist,
  daß die Fahrbereiche geregelt werden.

 Beschleunigungs-Rampen:
  Desweiteren gibt es nun eine Beschleunigungsrampe in 4 Stufen,
  die mit einer Taste durchgeschaltet werden können.
  Hier werden das Anzugverhalten beim Beschleunigen
  und reduzieren der Fahrgeschwindigkeit beeinflusst.
  Sanft und mit Gefühl oder volle Power und ruppig.
  Mit schweren Geräten oder Anhänger,
  kann es zu hohen Drücken im Planetengetriebe kommen und es kann Schaden nehmen!
  Hier sollte die Beschleunigungsrampe auf 3 oder weniger eingestellt werden.
  Stufe 4 ist eher für Leerfahrten geeignet.
  In der leichten Feldarbeit kann man ruhig auf Fahrstufe 1
  in der Beschleunigungsrampe 4 ziehen - Beispielsweise Scheibenegge, Flachgrubber.

Weitere detaillierte Erklärungen der Einzelheiten
gibt es im Escape Hilfemenü und
im Wiki auf Github, sowie Tutorial Videos.

So gut wie alle Werte und Einstellungen können mit FS22_DashboardLive verwendet werden.
Genauere Informationen dazu im Wiki auf Github.

Ideen und Feedback sowie Reports gerne unter <a href"https://github.com/s4t4n/FS22_CVT_Addon">Github: FS22_CVT_Addon</a> bereitstellen.
]]></de>
    </description> 

    <iconFilename>icon_CVT_Addon.dds</iconFilename>
	<multiplayer supported="true" />
    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="registerCVT_Addon.lua" />
    </extraSourceFiles>
	
	<l10n filenamePrefix="l10n/modDesc_l10n"/>

	<actions>
        <action name="LMBF_TOGGLE_RAMP" />
        <action name="LMBF_TOGGLE_RAMPT" />
        <action name="LMBF_TOGGLE_RAMPD" />
		<action name="LMBF_TOGGLE_BRAMP" />
        <action name="SETVARIOONE" />
        <action name="SETVARIOTWO" />
        <action name="SETVARIOTOGGLE" />
        <!-- <action name="SETVARION" /> -->
        <action name="SETVARIOADIFFS" />
        <action name="SETVARIORPM_AXIS" />
        <action name="SETVARIOCLUTCH_AXIS" />
        <!-- <action name="SETVARIORPMP" /> -->
        <!-- <action name="SETVARIORPMM" /> -->
        <!-- <action name="SETVARIORPMDMAX" /> -->
        <action name="SETPEDALTMS" />
    </actions>
	<inputBinding>
		<actionBinding action="SETVARIOONE">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="SETVARIOTWO">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="SETVARIOTOGGLE">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="LMBF_TOGGLE_RAMP">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="LMBF_TOGGLE_RAMPT">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="LMBF_TOGGLE_RAMPD">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="LMBF_TOGGLE_BRAMP">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<!-- <actionBinding action="SETVARION"> -->
			<!-- <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" /> -->
		<!-- </actionBinding> -->
		<actionBinding action="SETVARIOADIFFS">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="SETVARIORPM_AXIS">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<actionBinding action="SETVARIOCLUTCH_AXIS">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
		<!-- <actionBinding action="SETVARIORPMP"> -->
			<!-- <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" /> -->
		<!-- </actionBinding> -->
		<!-- <actionBinding action="SETVARIORPMM"> -->
			<!-- <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" /> -->
		<!-- </actionBinding> -->
		<!-- <actionBinding action="SETVARIORPMDMAX"> -->
			<!-- <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" /> -->
		<!-- </actionBinding> -->
		<actionBinding action="SETPEDALTMS">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="" />
		</actionBinding>
	</inputBinding>
	
</modDesc>